ALUSINE JALLOH

FULL STACK WFB DEVELOPER

Email | Github | LinkedIn | Twitter | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full Stack Software Developer with an Information Technology background and 4+ years of Freelance Experience. I specialize in Java, JavaScript, React, Ruby, and Flutter. Collaborated with cross-functional teams to deliver projects on time and within budget, resulting in a 90% project success rate.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Flutter, Kotlin, and WordPress.

Back-End: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Ruby, Java, PHP, and C++.

Tools & Methods: Linux/Unix & Windows Servers, GitHub, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD. Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Communication, Time Management, Adaptability

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Mastered intermediate and advanced topics in full-stack development (including Rails, Git, and DS&A challenges) while building 20+ full-stack projects independently and via pair programming. Some of them are listed below:

MICROVERSE Remote

Code Reviewer(Part-Time)

May 2023 - Present

- Provide quality and timely feedback to our students on their technical projects, so that they can become better software developers.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance by 10% in the quarter of work and Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

Remote

Full Stack Web Developer

August 2022 - Present

<u>Space X Booking</u> | <u>Live demo</u> – a web-based app which is showing information about spaceX rockets and missions.

- Led the development of the App. Wrote 100% of the logic, and 30% of the front-end code and reviewed the rest.
- Suggested advancement of security and confidentiality of data by implementing key protocols.
- Built with: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Redux, and WebPack.

World-Health-Assembly | Live demo - The Seventy-fifth World Health Assembly is the decision-making body of WHO.

- Single Handedly designed and developed a processing platform, which resulted in improved general performance.
- Identified areas for modification and improvements within a short time.

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

August 2022 - Present

Mentored more than 6 junior web developers, and provided technical support through 50+ code reviews per week.

FIX SOLUTION

Freetown, Sierra Leone

Software Engineer

January 2018 - January 2020

- Planned high-end software based on tracking rape victims' data in my state, which led to the overall efficiency of the company's processes by 25%.
- Introduced a solid database and GUI to identify user needs with 95% accuracy.
- Assumed leadership role in mobile development, directing a team that completed 95% of assigned tasks on time, fostering a strong sense of collaboration and cooperation.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE July 2022 – Present

Remote Full-stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

LIMKOKWING UNIVERSITY OF CREATIVE TECHNOLOGY

August 2016 - May 2022

Bsc honors in Information Technology

- Developed A Database Management System for the National Teaching Force as my thesis.
- Award: Graduated with First Class (Distinction).